to to this point Still a little
bit more work to do but really
appreciate everything
questions? Right I know you know
how serious you you take every
draft but you know we was
talking to
Dan and some of the guys down
there ride and they were saying
"This year you skipped out on
this meeting to focus that much
more on the draft So just talk
about you know the the how what
do you feel any pressure or
anything to get it right even
more just to talk about how much
more emphasis you putting on
have to even skip out and just
be that that focus and that
dialed in. Uh well you know it
was really more so um in the
past where I've gotten for our
process um it's
a lot of time that you miss and
so by the time that you get get
back back you're kind of in a
I'm kind of in kind of a makeup
mode because of all the time
that you miss for our process So
that's why um I just kind of
just said you know look look um
in order
for me to kind of try to avoid
being in that makeup mode
because now you hop into
draft meetings with the scouts
and blah blah blah and it's just
rolling but you miss miss a good
chunk of time for us and so um
that was that's what went into
it sure we haven't really
talked to you since free agency
so can you just um um see add
any topline guys not that we
expected you know the biggest uh
cost to free agents um but how
do you feel like you address
your your
needs and you know filled
whatever holes you you you
thought you had had yeah i mean
i feel like uh we did the best
we could and we um we
maximized the resources that we
had had available and that's
that's my job to do that and I
think that we accomplish that.
You referred to uh
financial constraints How how do
you imagine that that evolving
over the next couple years Like
when you look at your
cap table do you do you kind of
feel like you'll be in that
place indefinitely Um or do you
think there's a chance anything
changes changes over the next
couple years in that regard? I
mean yeah I mean it's look every
single year is different Um you
know you just you just don't
don't know Um you know but
yeah I mean It's look every
single year is different Um you
know you just you just don't
know Um you know but yeah there
there were some there there were
some things that we are are
currently navigating through but
I do think that they're good
problems um that we are
navigating through and
um you know I would much rather
have the good problems that we
have to navigate through
whatever the the the term I use
financial constraints whatever
it is but uh but at the end of
the day I I think they're good
problems I'd rather have those
problems any other way but it
could it it could change
I don't know what next year's
going to bring you know um Um
but you know we'll just um but
we'll we'll be prepared and
we'll adjust. It seemed like you
had another
follow. Well I was going to say
that and you you also meant the
one-year deals give you a lot of
flexibility I'm just curious
what are some other I guess
strategies or mechanisms that
you can use as a a GM to um you
know maintain that flexibility
outside of one-year deals. Uh
you mean to just add
more of multi-year deals? No no
I'm just I'm asking outside
of one-year deal like how what
are some other strategies that
you use use to maintain roster
flexibility on a year-to-year
basis? Oh there's a lot of
levers that you have at your
disposal Uh you just have to
just know know when is the right
time You got to be very
strategic You got to be smart
when to use those
levers But there's there's
multiple things that you can do
from a roster construction
construction standpoint Um but
you know but again like I say
each year's different So there's
times where it might make sense
to to trade a player It might
make sense to trade for a player
It might you know might help
you out from a salary standpoint
So every single year is
different Uh uh but we we have
we we do a lot of hard work on
that stuff on the front end Make
sure we're prepared and we'll
adjust accordingly. Right now
that you've done um your full
evaluations the team team sits
at number 17 Do
you have 17 first round grades
on some of the pro on the
prospects And just give me your
thoughts on the overall class
and be able potentially in the
first round Yeah Um we're not
there yet uh in terms of um you
know um having a absolute count
in terms of um we we still have
some more work to to do um um
you know in the this week
for sure Um so we're not there
yet Um but we feel pretty good
Um
you know I I I think we'll still
be able to be uh uh able to get
a good player Um
I do think that the this draft
is not too much different than
what's what's been in the past
probably couple years Um so uh
but
but I I do feel obviously we're
picking higher than we have been
in the past So hopefully that'll
put us in position to get a
better player. Seen some reports
in recent weeks that like
national reports they expect it
to be be a trade heavy first
round Are you getting an
inclination of that? I have not
Um it's probably probably it's a
little so early um that that
that action You know usually
calls will start to
happen Um but um we haven't
gotten to that point yet Um but
it could be Brad Brad the
balance uh in the draft between
getting a guy who you think
might be impact
immediately or more long-term
Has that that balance changed
over the last couple of years as
new challenges have presented
for your roster. No it's it's
it's a fair
question Um Um I always think
you know because like I've
always said the reason why we
always go like the best player
available approach is
because there is is only one
draft and the roster is going to
change every
single year every single year is
going to be new needs going to
be you know
contracts are going to expire
things are going to happen So
what may not seem as immediate I
I need this right now for this
year That might not be the case
for the next year So um so that
that's what's that that's what's
been our approach on on
that Um but you know there there
there's times where you might
you know it it lines up Like I
said maybe the best player is a
perceived need and it lines up
that way It's
it's lined up like like that in
the past but um but that's not
always the case. Brad you've had
you've had
some success drafting some
players who are injured like J
J Mo Uh and obviously you've had
some others have gone the other
way other way like like
like Handon How do you decide
how you're going to take an an
injured player? Yeah it depends
on what the injury is Uh it
depends on
uh uh you know what the injury
history has been in the past Um
so
you know like take like Jo you
know that was was you know
really his first major
injury Uh we felt pretty good
about what the injury was and
felt pretty good about with with
the with where medical
advancements are at this point
Um we felt pretty good about
that The same same thing with
with with Hinden I don't I don't
think Hinden uh I don't think
his injury was the reason of
why it didn't work out that way
But um but yeah you just got to
look at everything Um you know
it's it's just you just got to
feel good about it But it's case
by case for sure. One of the
things we're seeing with the
with NIL is is players staying a
little bit longer in college
I'm just curious when it it
comes to age with the draft when
you're evaluating tape of say a
24 or 25 year old does that have
to be a little bit cleaner tape
knowing that you want maybe
instant instant impact whereas
20 21 year old you can project a
little bit see
a little bit I'm just curious
how you approach kind of the age
element of the draft that we've
seen now older players before.
Yeah No and and Tim I think it
goes both ways It just it dep um
you you know you know what has
the tape looked like How
consistent has a player been
for an older player uh older
coming out in the draft So if
it's 24 25 years old uh now
first of all you got to have to
start adjusting as well because
like
you said these kids are staying
in a much longer time so you're
going to to get some older
prospects So um maybe some
certain positions that maturity
helps you know some sometimes it
may be a little bit more of a
warning warning sign Um but
it is something that we've had
adjusted to Um but you know uh I
think it's
it's it's it's case by case Uh
you know it just depends on the
player depends on the position
It's a lot of factors that that
go into it. Like one of the
topics associated with that is
like so many people speculate
about well he's going to be 30
when a second contract rolls
around Like how much weight do
you put into that? Yeah No you
you got to be prepared for that
because because it's it's real
man So like you say like look
you guys 24 25 years old now you
know and you know he's going to
be be looking at 30 you know by
the time the second contract
comes Okay So how much longevity
it is Maybe he hadn't played a
long time and he doesn't have as
much much wear and
tear but you know father time is
father time too So but you you
have to look at all of
it And uh again it's it's case
by case but it it is real
though. Defensive end what
what's your confidence in in
right tackle and defensive end
what's your confidence level in
Borum and Wam if if those guys
you know that that they can be
every down starter types or do
you have to you know supplement
that in the draft? Yeah I mean
uh I' I've said in the past um I
think I
thought Borne put out good tape
this this year Um I don't I
don't foresee that you know you
don't have a crystal ball but
from what last thing I saw on
tape you know I do think that
that he's got stability and same
as Wanam you know you got you're
talking about guys that have
been starters
in the NFL Um but just kind of
look at where the the trend is
going where the arrow is going
The last time they're still
young Um but uh we we we feel
good
about both of them so we don't
feel like it's you know um we
have to supplement them because
out there that you aren't doing
a
local pro date this this year Um
just kind of curious uh why you
made that
decision. Yeah just internally
you know we just kind of made a
decision to kind of just um
utilize that that time on for
some other things but still uh
uh still utilize the local
visits as well So we still
utilize the local visits but
we're just not we just
made the decision really uh last
last summer to do away with uh
Proday
and we'll see how it goes If we
feel like we miss something um
by not doing doing it then we'll
look at it and adjust again, not
to show your hand too much but
how many offensive
tackles do you see in in that
first round or even in the
second round as potential
first day starters in this
draft. Man I I I think think
anytime you're deal anytime
you're dealing with a rookie I
don't care where you draft them
at you know you're
going to have to be prepared for
a little bit of growth growth
period So um it's just
it's it's it's hard to say Um
some some guys may be a little
bit more ready but you know you
just never know So I can't
really give you really a good
answer
on that one in terms of day one
right now because any anytime
anytime
you draft a rookie I think
you're going to have to be
prepared for for some
development growth period this
year and um are deeper than
others and within our other
stuff are you getting older
draft class now overall guys
stay yeah I mean that's
just been the nature of you know
whether it's nil or you know the
covid period starting to come to
a close um you're just you're
you're getting more older
players um but that it it
doesn't it doesn't scare us away
from you know not
picking a player uh just because
he's a little more advanced in
age or anything but yeah that
has been a little bit more
prevalent because of both uh
kids staying in school longer
and then you know know there's
still some little trickle down
from CO as well still. Was it
a draft or is this a normal
draft compared to other? I think
it's very similar to the past
couple of of drafts Um you know
when the whole um when the
amount of underassmen
underassmen that would enter the
draft kind of
drastically fell off So that's
that's why I would compare it to
the past couple of drafts. You
open this up every year with
gratitude for your staff. Just
want to
dig a little deeper there with
with a a specific staff member
You you promoted Brian Hudith uh
three years ago
and know you go way back Covered
kind of the same area of the
country for a while Just curious
curious um I guess he speak a
lot in superpowers you know what
what's Brian's superpower in his
role? Yeah he just has a lot of
experience Um he's he's very
organized He's a good
evaluator Um you know I used to
be like you mentioned um being
out in the southeast with Hudith
and kind of seeing the way he
goes about his work Um you know
as much
as scouting is evolving uh you
still need to have
some old school roots you know
and there's some there there's
there's still some
grassroot level things that you
can't there there's steps you
cannot skip basically
in the scouting process And
that's what I really appreciate
about HUD is HUD is going to
make sure that
those steps aren't aren't
getting skipped because they're
critical evolved though from
year to year z like do you still
have the same level of anxiety
from the first year or it just
seems like you making all these
different changes like how much
has your draft process evolved
has it gotten better like
just going in this year like
kind of your mindset entering
this year's draft? Yeah we've I
think we've evolved a lot um you
know it's something that we take
a long hard look at uh after
each draft to you know see
things that that we like that
that we're doing things that we
could
tweak things that we could do
better and implement those
things and just see how it goes
But you know I think important
to first of all you can't can't
be scared to upate those
evolutions but also you got to
look back at and make sure that
they were the right things And
uh there's sometimes where you
tried something and and it you
didn't get the results that you
really wanted and you know you
got to tweak again So um but uh
yeah we we have had had a lot of
evolution
from the first time but the one
thing that has not changed and
that has stayed consistent is
the film And you know that's
that's first and and foremost Um
that's the reason why we're
acquiring these players is to be
good football players
So that part really hasn't
evolved Um Um I mean that part
hasn't changed but we
definitely made a lot of
evolutions in other areas. Brad
going back to to Brad's question
about the offensive tackles for
a minute Yeah, it does seem like
like as many as seven offensive
tackles have been projected or
mahawk to to go in the first
round Just what's your
evaluation of the top of the
offensive tackle class And do
you guys feel like that's a
long-term need for you guys? Uh
I mean I think anytime you can
acquire an
offensive tackle that's a good
good player Um you know I always
think you know if you look at it
like an offensive tackle or you
know uh you know you call that
premium position
category Um you know I don't
think you can ever really have
enough of
them Those guys are hard to find
Um but you know you got to make
sure that you get the right one
But
um but you know I think there's
some there's some good ones you
know Uh we'll just kind of see
how it falls. What are the the
premium positions in your eyes?
What are the premium
positions Well based on what you
guys have always said,
no but I mean but you guys guys
tell us what the premium
positions are right? Said
premium position to his question
so I didn't know if you had your
own definition of premium
position So the positions that
we did not draft in
2023 that's the the that's those
are the you know those are the
positions right? I mean I think
most people think pass rusher
quarterback offensive tackle So
I don't know if you
align align with that your
original lines with that agree
at cornerback I don't know if
that's a premium position How
does how does Terion's situation
play play into you
know any needs or you know that
you may have or what you may do
in the draft? Um you know
um we've put out statements
about about that There's no
updates with the draft
development and resign model
that you guys have implemented
how
much much harder now given where
you're drafting because of the
success you've had
and also the fact that you've
had fewer picks in the top 100
than say you did earlier in your
tenure. How does it affect
things? Yeah How harder is it to
implement that model
uh the draft develop and resign
when you have fewer picks in
that that
top 100 range. I mean it it it
doesn't really really pose a
challenge in terms of the
acquisition of the players Um
you know look uh there's
there's a lot of different ways
that you navigate navigate with
having less picks Um
look you might have a lot of
picks you know and that might
not be the case on on drafting
in terms of what you trade what
you acquire all that kind of
stuff But um but yeah that's
that's kind of what you want If
you can get a good football
player that that ends up fitting
the vision that you had
and you know um he makes it to
where he's earned a second
contract You know that's That's
that's really what what you want
Um but you know that
doesn't that doesn't always
affect but it doesn't affect
like whether you have mix or
bless
bless picks Um you know that
model that we have used used in
the past uh I don't I don't see
that changing with the amount of
pixel have. I'm sorry Brad that
drafting and then as a as the
defense is currently currently
constituted are are you
confident that it's
championship level at this at
this stage as the defense is.
Yeah I mean I that's those are
our hopes you know that's you
know um look we're we're never
going to be satisfied
uh in terms of of where we're at
you know Um you know and that's
what me and Dan are always
constantly constantly looking at
man We're always constantly
looking at person and how
to add more and tweaks and like
like all this stuff you know